<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documents on EnzymeML Project</title>
    <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documents on EnzymeML Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://EnzymeML.org/documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Specifications</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/specifications/</guid>
      <description>The EnzymeML specifications define the syntax and semantics of EnzymeML. These documents are the definitive references for EnzymeML. They will be made available upon submission of our first paper. Please state tune for future updates.
STRENDA Guidelines EnzymeML helps you to implement the STRENDA Guidelines. These guidelines aim to support authors to comprehensively report kinetic and equilibrium data from their investigations of enzyme activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use cases</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/cases/</guid>
      <description>Here you will find details of selected case studies applying EnzymeML for experimentalists, modelers and software developers
Original Peer Review Papers  Paper 1 Paper 2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/publications/</guid>
      <description>This section lists published papers and chapters describing EnzymeML and core EnzymeML-supporting software tools.
Original Peer Review Papers  Paper 1 Paper 2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software and Databases Guide</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/guide/</guid>
      <description>The EnzymeML Software and Database Guide provides a summary of all EnzymeML-compatible software systems and databases currently available.
COPASI COPASI is a software application for simulation and analysis of biochemical networks and their dynamics. COPASI is a stand-alone program that supports models in the SBML standard and can simulate their behavior using ODEs or Gillespie&amp;rsquo;s stochastic simulation algorithm; arbitrary discrete events can be included in such simulations. COPASI is a versatile with powerful features for representing enzyme models, simulation, and data analysis, visulaization and output.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>