<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on EnzymeML Project</title>
    <link>http://EnzymeML.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on EnzymeML Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:01:34 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://EnzymeML.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EnzymeML 1.0 released</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/news/enzymeml_1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/news/enzymeml_1-0/</guid>
      <description>The specifications for Release 1.0 of EnzymeML are now under preprapration and will be abailable from the Downloads page.
Preprint submitted The EnzymeML team submitted the first version of EnzymeML for publication. The reference for the preprint is:
 Range J, Halupczok C, Lohmann J, Swainston N, Kettner C, Bergmann FT, Weidemann A, Wittig U, Schnell S, Pleiss J (2020). EnzymeML – a data exchange format for biocatalysis and enzymology. Preprint  Please state tune for future updates about our first release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juergen Pleiss</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/juergen-pleiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/juergen-pleiss/</guid>
      <description>Bioinformatics Group Leader, Institute of Biochemistry and Technical Biochemistry, University of Stuttgart, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEnzyme</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/jenzyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/jenzyme/</guid>
      <description>JEnzyme is a free, open-source, pure-Java library for working with EnzymeML. It helps to read and write EnzymeML documents.
STRENDA Guidelines The STRENDA Guidelines are available on&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specifications</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/specifications/</guid>
      <description>The EnzymeML specifications define the syntax and semantics of EnzymeML. These documents are the definitive references for EnzymeML. They will be made available upon submission of our first paper. Please state tune for future updates.
STRENDA Guidelines EnzymeML helps you to implement the STRENDA Guidelines. These guidelines aim to support authors to comprehensively report kinetic and equilibrium data from their investigations of enzyme activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neil Swainston</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/neil-swainston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:30 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/neil-swainston/</guid>
      <description>Senior Research Associate, Institute of Integrative Biology in the University of Liverpool, UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For experimentalists</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/experimentalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/experimentalists/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you to manage your experimental data?
Managing experimental data with EnzymeML   Measured time course data on substrate and/or product concentrations is saved in the same document with metadata about the enzyme and the reaction conditions. This faciliates replicability and reproducibility of experimental assays.
  EnzymeML documents are standardized, so their format is independent of the experimental scientist. Documents are machine- and human-readable. Markup languanges (ML) are specifically designed for machines, and therefore they are not optimally for user reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyEnzyme</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/pyenzyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/pyenzyme/</guid>
      <description>JEnzyme is a free, open-source, Python library for working with EnzymeML. It helps to read and write EnzymeML documents.
Original Peer Review Papers  Paper 1 Paper 2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use cases</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/cases/</guid>
      <description>In this page, you will find find details of selected case studies applying EnzymeML for experimentalists, modelers and software developers.
Original Peer Review Papers The first case studies are decribed in our preprint below.
 Range J, Halupczok C, Lohmann J, Swainston N, Kettner C, Bergmann FT, Weidemann A, Wittig U, Schnell S, Pleiss J (2020). EnzymeML – a data exchange format for biocatalysis and enzymology. Preprint  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/publications/</guid>
      <description>This section lists published papers and chapters describing EnzymeML and core EnzymeML-supporting software tools.
Original Peer Review Papers   Malzacher S, Range J, Halupczok C, Pleiss J, Rother D (2020). BioCatHub, a graphical user interface for standardized data acquisition in biocatalysis. Chemie Ingenieur Technik 92, 1251-1251. https://doi.org/10.1002/cite.202055297
  Range J, Halupczok C, Lohmann J, Swainston N, Kettner C, Bergmann FT, Weidemann A, Wittig U, Schnell S, Pleiss J (2020).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frank T. Bergmann</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/frank-bergmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:23 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/frank-bergmann/</guid>
      <description>Modeling of Biological Processes Group in Centre for Organismal Studies, Heidelberg University, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For modelers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/modelers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/modelers/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you developing, implementing and analysing models? Here we present you one example to illustrate the power of EnzymeML for modelers.
Kinetic modeling of EnzymeML data with COPASI Experimental data on enzyme kinetics (reaction conditions, enzyme concentration, time course of substrate and product concentrations) is stored in a single EnzymeML document and can uploaded to the biochemical system simulator COPASI. Within COPASI, different reaction mechanisms can be tested by selecting different kinetic laws and estimating kinetic parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specific APIs</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/api/</guid>
      <description>A free, open-source API library for working with EnzymeML content. It presently supports COPASI, SABIO-RK and STRENDA DB.
Original Peer Review Papers  Paper 1 Paper 2 This is a test  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santiago Schnell</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/santiago-schnell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/santiago-schnell/</guid>
      <description>Interim Chair, Department of Molecular &amp;amp; Integrative Physiology, University of Michigan Medical School, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For software developers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/software/</guid>
      <description>Want to implement EnzymeML read and write functionalities in your software or database? Here we present you an example to inspire your team.
EnzymeML is compatible with SMBL EnzymeML is an extension of SBML. All additional information that are specific to enzyme-catalyzed are added as annotation in a standard SBML file. Thus, EnzymeML is compatible with SBML.
You can easily implement an EnzymeML read and write functionality for software applications, such as electronic lab notebooks, laboratory information management systems, modelling platforms, or databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software and Databases Guide</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/guide/</guid>
      <description>The EnzymeML Software and Database Guide provides a summary of all EnzymeML-compatible software systems and databases currently available.
COPASI COPASI is a software application for simulation and analysis of biochemical networks and their dynamics. COPASI is a stand-alone program that supports models in the SBML standard and can simulate their behavior using ODEs or Gillespie&amp;rsquo;s stochastic simulation algorithm; arbitrary discrete events can be included in such simulations. COPASI is a versatile with powerful features for representing enzyme models, simulation, and data analysis, visulaization and output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validators</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/validators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/validators/</guid>
      <description>A portable, low-level, tools for annocating and validating EnzymeML files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carsten Kettner</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/carsten-kettner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:45:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/carsten-kettner/</guid>
      <description>STRENDA Commission Coordinator at the Beilstein-Institut, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ulrike Wittig</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/ulrike-wittig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/ulrike-wittig/</guid>
      <description>Scientific Databases and Visualization Group at the Heidelberg Institute for Theoretical Studies, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan Range</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/jan-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/jan-range/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andreas Weidemann</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/andreas-weidemann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/andreas-weidemann/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>EnzymeML Project Contacts For questions, suggestions, or participation in the EnzymeML project, please contact the project coordinators: Jürgen Pleiss, Neil Swainston, or Santiago Schnell.
STRENDA Guidelines If you are interested to learn more about the STRENDA Guidelines, please contact Carsten Kettner.
Website Santiago Schnell is the primary contact for the website updates. This website was developed by modying the Hugo Serif theme by zerostatic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>