<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on EnzymeML Project</title>
    <link>http://EnzymeML.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on EnzymeML Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 17:01:34 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://EnzymeML.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EnzymeML 1.0 released</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/news/enzymeml_1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/news/enzymeml_1-0/</guid>
      <description>The specifications for EnzymeML 1.0 are now available from the Downloads page. Additionally, EnzymeML team submitted for our first paper for publication.
The reference for the preprint is:
 Range J, Halupczok C, Lohmann J, Swainston N, Kettner C, Bergmann FT, Weidemann A, Wittig U, Schnell S, Pleiss J (2020). EnzymeML – a data exchange format for biocatalysis and enzymology. https://www.EnzymeML.org  You can download our preprint and supporting information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juergen Pleiss</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/juergen-pleiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/juergen-pleiss/</guid>
      <description>Bioinformatics Group Leader, Institute of Biochemistry and Technical Biochemistry, University of Stuttgart, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specific APIs</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/api/</guid>
      <description>An application programming interface (API) which consists of two libraries, the Python library PyEnzyme, and the Java library JEnzyme, which support reading, writing, editing, merging, and visualization of EnzymeML documents.
Presently, we have three application-specific thin API layers COPASI, STRENDA DB and SABIO-RK. They are available to download in the links below:
 TL_COPASI TL_STRENDA TL_BioCatNet  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specifications</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/specifications/</guid>
      <description>The EnzymeML specifications define the syntax and semantics of EnzymeML. These documents are the definitive references for EnzymeML.
STRENDA Guidelines EnzymeML helps you to implement the STRENDA Guidelines. These guidelines aim to support authors to comprehensively report kinetic and equilibrium data from their investigations of enzyme activities.
Structure of EnzymeML document An EnzymeML document consists of three file types: a file using SBML to describe the experimental reaction conditions, the kinetic model, and the kinetic parameters, CSV (comma-separated values)-formatted files to store the time courses of substrate and product concentrations, and a manifest file lists the content of the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neil Swainston</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/neil-swainston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:30 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/neil-swainston/</guid>
      <description>Senior Research Associate, Institute of Integrative Biology in the University of Liverpool, UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For experimentalists</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/experimentalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/experimentalists/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you to manage your experimental data?
EnzymeML was developed to support data acquisition, data analysis, and sharing of data by providing a standardized exchange format for enzymatic data. EnzymeML follows the Standards of Reporting Enzymology Data (STRENDA) Guidelines, a comprehensive set of metadata describing reaction conditions and kinetic models. EnzymeML is written in eXtensible Markup Language (XML).
It builds on the well-established Systems Biology Markup Language (SBML) and includes information about the enzyme, the substrate(s) and product(s), the reaction conditions, the selected kinetic model, and estimated kinetic parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native EnzymeML tools</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/byenzymeml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/byenzymeml/</guid>
      <description>We provide multiple native software solutions for you, either if you are an experimentalist using EnzymeML to document your experiments or a database provider to integrate our data model into your system.
Spreadsheet to EnzymeML conversion Download the EnzymeML spreadsheet template and fill in your experimental data. Once done, you can use our template conversion page to convert your spreadsheet to an EnzymeML document.
For further information, please contact us or investiagte the example sheet that is included in the EnzymeML spreadsheet template archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Programming Interface</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/api/</guid>
      <description>An application programming interface (API) which consists of two libraries, the Python library PyEnzyme, and the Java library JEnzyme, which support reading, writing, editing, merging, and visualization of EnzymeML documents.
API description The API uses the SBML syntax and naming conventions which are familiar to enzymologists to be implemented into EnzymeML. The basic concept of the two libraries is the usage of multiple dictionaries, in which proteins, reactants, units, and reactions are stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyEnzyme</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/pyenzyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/pyenzyme/</guid>
      <description>The Python library PyEnzyme is part of the EnzymeML application programming interface (API). It supports reading, writing, editing, merging, and visualization of EnzymeML documents.
The library JEnzyme was built based on its respective SBML counterparts libsbml. It can be downloaded here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frank T. Bergmann</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/frank-bergmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:23 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/frank-bergmann/</guid>
      <description>Modeling of Biological Processes Group in Centre for Organismal Studies, Heidelberg University, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For modelers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/modelers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/modelers/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you developing, implementing and analysing models?
An EnzymeML document provides the complete experimental information including the enzyme concentration, the initial concentrations of substrates, products, or inhibitors, and the measured concentrations of substrate or product at different time points. It might also provide a preferred kinetic model or alternative kinetic models. The model consists of a kinetic law which determines the temporal changes in the concentration of substrates, products, or enzyme as a function of measured concentrations of substrates, products, and enzyme, and of kinetic parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JEnzyme</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/jenzyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/jenzyme/</guid>
      <description>The Java library JEnzyme is part of the EnzymeML application programming interface (API). It supports reading, writing, editing, merging, and visualization of EnzymeML documents.
The library JEnzyme was built based on its respective SBML counterparts JSBML. It can be downloaded here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use cases</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/cases/</guid>
      <description>To illustrate the power of EnzymeML, we illustrate selected applications for experimental enzymologists, system biology modelers, and software developers. More applications are available in our EnzymeML preprint, which can be downloaded in our Publications page.
Creating EnzymeML documents from spreadsheets In the absence of a standard format, experimentalists typically store their experimental time course data in a spreadsheet following an ad hoc structure. Recently, a CSV-formatted spreadsheet, the BioCatNet template, was proposed to store and report experimental data on enzyme-catalyzed reactions according to the STRENDA Guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santiago Schnell</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/santiago-schnell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/santiago-schnell/</guid>
      <description>Chair, Department of Molecular &amp;amp; Integrative Physiology, University of Michigan Medical School, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For database providers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/database/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you to publish results and to exchange data?
EnzymeML is a flexible data model for biocatalysis and enzymology capable to completely describe an experiment in a machine-readable format. In order to handle and integrate EnzymeML in your database, we provide our software solution PyEnzyme, which can be either installed locally or reached via several endpoints of our REST-API.
Currently implemented functionalities Validation of minimal requirements and upload to SABIO-RK PyEnzyme as well as our REST-API provide an interface to validate incoming EnzymeML documents to comply with the minimal requirements necessary for a succesful upload to your database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For software developers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/software/</guid>
      <description>Want to implement EnzymeML read and write functionalities in your software? Here you have somes ideas to inspire your team.
EnzymeML documents EnzymeML follows the Standards of Reporting Enzymology Data (STRENDA) Guidelines, a comprehensive set of metadata describing reaction conditions and kinetic models. EnzymeML is written in eXtensible Markup Language (XML). It builds on the well-established Systems Biology Markup Language (SBML) and includes information about the enzyme, the substrate(s) and product(s), the reaction conditions, the selected kinetic model, and estimated kinetic parameters (find the XML schema definition here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the community</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/contribute/</guid>
      <description>How can you contribute to EnzymeML?   More applications which read and write EnzymeML
As a standardized exchange format for enzymatic data, EnzymeML offers the opportunity to exchange data between different applications without need of reformatting. We currently collaborate with software developers and database providers to enable their applications to read and write EnzymeML (find technical details here).
  Extension of the data model
Currently, an EnzymeML document contains information about reaction conditions (temperature, buffer, additives) and about the enzyme, the substrates, and the products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software and Databases Guide</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/guide/</guid>
      <description>The EnzymeML Software and Database Guide provides a summary of all EnzymeML-compatible software systems and databases currently available.
COPASI COPASI is a software application for simulation and analysis of biochemical networks and their dynamics. COPASI is a stand-alone program that supports models in the SBML standard and can simulate their behavior using ODEs or Gillespie&amp;rsquo;s stochastic simulation algorithm; arbitrary discrete events can be included in such simulations. COPASI is a versatile with powerful features for representing enzyme models, simulation, and data analysis, visulaization and output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validators</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/validators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/downloads/validators/</guid>
      <description>EnzymeML has specific validation tool guarantees compatibility with SBML. Further application-specific validation tools have been added, such as a STRENDA DB validator to check for compatibility with the STRENDA Guidelines.
The validators are part of application-specific thin API layers COPASI, STRENDA DB and SABIO-RK. They are available to download in the links below:
 TL_COPASI TL_STRENDA TL_BioCatNet  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/documents/publications/</guid>
      <description>This section lists preprints and published work describing EnzymeML and core EnzymeML-supporting software tools.
Original Peer Review Papers   Malzacher S, Range J, Halupczok C, Pleiss J, Rother D (2020). BioCatHub, a graphical user interface for standardized data acquisition in biocatalysis. Chemie Ingenieur Technik 92, 1251-1251. https://doi.org/10.1002/cite.202055297
  Range J, Halupczok C, Lohmann J, Swainston N, Kettner C, Bergmann FT, Weidemann A, Wittig U, Schnell S, Pleiss J (2020).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carsten Kettner</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/carsten-kettner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:45:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/carsten-kettner/</guid>
      <description>STRENDA Commission Coordinator at the Beilstein-Institut, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ulrike Wittig</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/ulrike-wittig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/ulrike-wittig/</guid>
      <description>Scientific Databases and Visualization Group at the Heidelberg Institute for Theoretical Studies, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Dienhart</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/hannah-dienhart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/hannah-dienhart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan Range</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/jan-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/jan-range/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simone Lauterbach</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/simone-lauterbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/simone-lauterbach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephan Malzacher</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/stephan-malzacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/stephan-malzacher/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andreas Weidemann</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/team/andreas-weidemann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:44:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/team/andreas-weidemann/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community integrations</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/bycommunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/bycommunity/</guid>
      <description>Find tools developed by the community, which integrate the EnzymeML data model and software in various applications, such as databases or kinetic modeling.
BioCatHub Content soon to be added&amp;hellip;
SABIO-RK upload Content soon to be added&amp;hellip;
STRENDA-DB upload Content soon to be added&amp;hellip;
Dataverse integration Content soon to be added&amp;hellip;
Kinetic modeling via Jupyter Content soon to be added&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>EnzymeML Project Contacts For questions, suggestions, or participation in the EnzymeML project, please contact the project coordinators: Jürgen Pleiss, Neil Swainston, or Santiago Schnell.
STRENDA Guidelines If you are interested to learn more about the STRENDA Guidelines, please contact Carsten Kettner.
Website Please contact our webmaster. This website was developed by modying the Hugo Serif theme by zerostatic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
