<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What is EnzymeML on EnzymeML Project</title>
    <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What is EnzymeML on EnzymeML Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://EnzymeML.org/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For experimentalists</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/experimentalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/experimentalists/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you to manage your experimental data?
Managing experimental data with EnzymeML   Measured time course data on substrate and/or product concentrations is saved in the same document with metadata about the enzyme and the reaction conditions. This faciliates replicability and reproducibility of experimental assays.
  EnzymeML documents are standardized, so their format is independent of the experimental scientist. Documents are machine- and human-readable. Markup languanges (ML) are specifically designed for machines, and therefore they are not optimally for user reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For modelers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/modelers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/modelers/</guid>
      <description>How can EnzymeML help you developing, implementing and analysing models? Here we present you one example to illustrate the power of EnzymeML for modelers.
Kinetic modeling of EnzymeML data with COPASI Experimental data on enzyme kinetics (reaction conditions, enzyme concentration, time course of substrate and product concentrations) is stored in a single EnzymeML document and can uploaded to the biochemical system simulator COPASI. Within COPASI, different reaction mechanisms can be tested by selecting different kinetic laws and estimating kinetic parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For software developers</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/services/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/services/software/</guid>
      <description>Want to implement EnzymeML read and write functionalities in your software or database? Here you have somes ideas to inspire your team.
EnzymeML is compatible with SMBL EnzymeML is an extension of SBML. All additional information that are specific to enzyme-catalyzed are added as annotation in a standard SBML file. Thus, EnzymeML is compatible with SBML.
Application Programming Interface (API) We created an Application Programming Interface (API) to interface with three applications: COPASI, STRENDA DB and SABIO-RK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>