<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on EnzymeML Project</title>
    <link>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on EnzymeML Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://EnzymeML.org/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PyEnzyme</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/pyenzyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/pyenzyme/</guid>
      <description>PyEnzyme is a comprehensive software solution for manipulating EnzymeML files. Furthermore, the library incorporates convenient access to prominent modeling platforms, such as COPASI and PySCeS, enabling a smooth progression from laboratory experiments to kinetic characterization. Additionally, PyEnzyme empowers users to generate aesthetically appealing, publication-quality visualizations, as well as export data to widely utilized formats, such as CSV and JSON.
The API uses the SBML syntax and naming conventions which are familiar to enzymologists to be implemented into EnzymeML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST-API</title>
      <link>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://EnzymeML.org/tools/rest/</guid>
      <description>We understand the significance of embracing a language-independent methodology for data retrieval and parsing in the present interconnected application ecosystem. In light of this, we have made accessible a publicly available REST-API that incorporates a comprehensive array of endpoints, providing comprehensive EnzymeML handling capabilities. This API allows you to integrate PyEnzyme into your web-based toolkit, regardless of your technology stack, thereby granting you access to all the benefits of PyEnzyme without the need to program in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>